{
    "id": "9cbb73aac2434cb5a7454b3235e747a0",
    "title": "Present continuous tense quiz",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Mother …………………. a cake for me.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is baking",
                "are baking",
                "was baking"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6b419c134e2d425986852d11f86e3416"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………. my breakfast.",
            "description": "When the subject is the first person singular noun 'I', we make the present continuous form by adding 'am' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "eat",
                "am eating",
                "are eating",
                "is eating"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b9344d87342648e3b3879b605baecc29"
        },
        {
            "question": "Suma ……………… for us.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is waiting",
                "are waiting",
                "am waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "69a8abb952ce42f3b1d5fd5d77bd9a72"
        },
        {
            "question": "Susie …………………. the flowers in the vase.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is arranging",
                "are arranging",
                "am arranging"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "811a913285ef44db9f6ab1319c746965"
        },
        {
            "question": "Rahul ………………. for his exams.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am studying",
                "are studying",
                "is studying"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3fe19235789b4249abb93fdbd3ab5752"
        },
        {
            "question": "Veena ……………….. the violin.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is playing",
                "am playing",
                "are playing"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "62f66dad89544355bcff53c3c2c15f45"
        },
        {
            "question": "My sister ………………. her homework.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "are doing",
                "am doing",
                "is doing"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4594ef1342814fc889880a9167a473eb"
        },
        {
            "question": "The girls ……………….. their dialogues.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense when the subject is a plural noun, we use 'are' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "are rehearsing",
                "is rehearsing",
                "am rehearsing"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e37b399914be4b26a7c72be938e9d33b"
        },
        {
            "question": "The cat ……………….. the mouse.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "am chasing",
                "is chasing",
                "are chasing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "509010a43fe84a5cab8aabb65b71953f"
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy ………………. water from the pond.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense, when the subject is a singular noun, we use 'is' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is fetching",
                "am fetching",
                "are fetching"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b31fee05398a4708aa3770593829bbff"
        },
        {
            "question": "The students .............................. their lessons.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense when the subject is a plural noun, we use 'are' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is learning",
                "am learning",
                "are learning"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1ff67eb2497e41c38b3c38faf59fd985"
        },
        {
            "question": "The children ................................ kites.",
            "description": "In the present continuous tense when the subject is a plural noun, we use 'are' before the ing form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is flying",
                "am flying",
                "are flying"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c928bb58a6984bdcb78968199eab3f32"
        }
    ]
}